RYAN M. OSTOLSKI, MBA, PMP, CSM

305 Brookhaven Ave Unit 850 • Atlanta GA 30319 • (404) 290-2231 • ryanostolski@gmail.com

EXPERIENCED IT PROJECT MANAGER

Effectively Integrating Technology with Business

Innovative and experienced project/program manager with a record of developing and supporting successful solutions incorporating a wide range of applications and technologies. Recognized for improving organizational effectiveness and efficiency through extensive experience in all areas of the project management lifecycle, including design, data analysis, and quality assurance.

Oversee and lead all phases of multiple projects including planning, technical oversight, resource management, and assessment of end-user needs while efficiently resolving issues. Exemplary track record in leading teams in strategic project initiatives and guiding companies through consultative process implementation techniques.

- Innovative and forward-thinking leader utilizing progressive methods for team building and knowledge transfer in various industries.
- Direct experience identifying risks, developing mitigations strategies and communicating potential impacts all while articulating the critical priorities and milestones to improve IT solutions.
- GE Energy Information Technology Leadership Program (ITLP)

CORE COMPETENCIES

Project Management • Process Re-engineering • Process Improvement • Performance Optimization Customer Relationship Management • Infrastructure Management • Technology Integration Business Strategy • Resource and Capacity Planning • Configuration • Quality Control Change Management • Business Analysis • Six Sigma • Agile/Kanban

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Core Security (formerly Courion Corporation), Roswell, GA *Professional Services Project Manager*

March 2015 to June 2016

Actively managed 20-30 consulting engagements with individual budgets ranging from 20k to 500k lasting 2 weeks-12 months, with each project at various stages to implement IAM & vulnerability solutions for customers in several different industries.

- Led a custom POC initiative delivering integrated functionality between two previously unrelated Core Security products with a 3rd party tool (splunk) directly in an early adopting customer's environment.
- Introduced new agile process/tools to the Professional Services organization to expedite the implementation of Core Security products to customers on time and on budget.
- Continuously developed a backlog of new requirements during and after customer engagements to directly introduce change requests to implement the additional scope requested or for the Sales team to follow up later as future revenue generating opportunities.
- Represented the company on a TAG Young Professionals panel discussing Project Management.

Aptean, Atlanta, GA

Sept 2013 to Jan 2015

Portfolio Project Manager

Introduced effective PMO practices for the R&D organization to establish common processes across all newly integrated product lines. Continuously drove performance improvements to reduce downtime and increase productivity across the organization.

- Led 2014 portfolio planning including 200+ marketable features across 10 product lines developed within 50+ projects over the course of the year.
- Persistently tracked portfolio status through establishing common reporting methodologies across all
 projects summarizing information in a high level and detailed weekly leadership report out to R&D
 and Product Management SVPs.

RYAN M. OSTOLSKI, PMP · Page 2 · ryanostolski@gmail.com

- Implemented new resource allocation strategies to align R&D resources by knowledge type instead of product type to streamline movement of resources between high priority company projects.
- Effectively coached team Project Managers on team processes and PMO methodologies.

Rideout App, Atlanta, GA *Co-Founder*

Jan 2014 to July 2014

Brought a mobile application from concept to prototype. Using the prototype we successfully completed a soft launch providing potential investors with the market potential of a fully developed application. We were unable to secure additional financing to bring the application to the next stage and closed the company.

- Developed application design and story boards then through consulting with offshore development teams developed an initial mobile application, backend database and company website.
- Soft launched the mobile application with 300+ registered customers and service providers.
- Created Business Plan and next steps to move from prototype to fully developed application.
- Engage multiple investment groups for additional funding and advisement including groups of disenfranchised service providers of a major competitor, Atlanta Tech Village and ATDC.

InterCall, Atlanta, GA

Jan 2013 to Sept 2013

Technical Project Manager

Oversaw development and implementation of a custom CRM software solution to support core company telecommunications and web conferencing products at multiple call center locations. Drove performance of team of 25, supporting project management processes, documenting agile project management, while administrating Jira/Confluence for other project teams to utilize. Administered budget of \$8M annually, with ROI of \$15M.

- Effectively increased user adoption implementing a new escalation process to expedite the development and implementation of critical CRM components.
- Created agile training material and coached project managers through agile processes to prepare them to implement Agile within their project teams.
- Decreased the new enhancement process from a three-year wait to a one-month turnaround on initial delivery of some functionality.
- Enhanced efficiencies in filtering user feedback into the right channel, issue, question and enhancement.

GE Energy

June 2010 to Oct 2012

ERP Implementation Leader, Atlanta, GA

Managed PMO IT Projects for an Oracle ERP Implementation, leading the conversions of Purchase Order and Project data sources. Introduced change management to minimize customizations to the ERP.

 Reduced Sabrix issues during invoicing by introducing new process improvements and minimizing customizations to the ERP system.

Engineering Tools Leader, Atlanta, GA

Managed Engineering tools for Digital Energy engineering, developing new system upgrade processes while partnering with Corporate IT teams. Collaborated with Application Support to support existing company applications under information technology control.

• Successfully reduced and eliminated costs on 165 corporate engineering tools.

Collaboration Tools Integration Leader, Belfort, France

Managed Collaboration Tools segment of an acquisition integration bringing the new Power Conversion business unit (previously known as Converteam) of 5,500 employees into GE Energy.

- Effectively executed on a global rollout of WebEx Connect and Audio (Conference & Mobile) products based on seven different regional requirements.
- Initiated planning for the migration of employees from Gmail to GE's Outlook environment.
- Planned and budgeted implementation of seven global Cisco Telepresence rooms.

RYAN M. OSTOLSKI, PMP · Page 3 · ryanostolski@gmail.com

IT Project Manager, Atlanta, GA

Managed Functional ID Project within the IT Governance group, implemented Quality Center 10 while leading the system integration and user acceptance testing. Trained users on all Functional ID enhancements to the Identity Management System, implemented process improvements for over 30 Oracle ERP applications.

Repairs SAP Operations Implementation Leader, Atlanta, GA

Managed Phase 1 Project Activities, leading user acceptance testing and training during phase 2 system integration testing to identify shop advocates to later increase user adoption rates. Trained multiple new SAP Operation Leaders through the Repairs SAP application.

The Home Depot, Atlanta, GA Systems Engineer

May 2007 to June 2010

Managed non-production store environments for numerous technical projects, leading initiation through to production release to over 2,000 store environments. Drove operations of 18 quality assurance laboratory environments in 3 countries, managing teams of offsite contractors in Canada and India. Developed database to track and plan the allocation of resources.

- Managed \$1M laboratory environment upgrade at all testing locations.
- Frequently visited THD stores to work alongside store associates to better understand their needs.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration

University of Georgia, Terry College of Business, Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Business Administration, Management Information Systems

Georgia College and State University, Milledgeville, GA

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional (PMP) – Project Management Institute

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) – Scrum Alliance

SELECT AWARDS

- 1. **GE Community Service Award -** significant participation and leadership in Atlanta volunteer events.
- 2. Pillars of Excellence Award above and beyond execution as an IT Systems Engineer.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

SharePoint • Team Foundation Server • SalesForce • VersionOne • JIRA • Greenhopper • Confluence • Quality Center • Microsoft Office Suite • Microsoft Project • Microsoft Outlook • Microsoft Visio

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Project Leader / Task Leader - Hands On Atlanta • Project Leader - Good Shepherd Services of Atlanta Task Leader - PAWS of Atlanta • ITLP Representative - GE Energy Atlanta Volunteer Council Former Advisor and Volunteer - Fuller Community Service • TAG Young Professionals